Joseph Mania

Nairobi, Kenya | +254 740 743 521 | martialmania19@gmail.com

Website: https://techmaniac649449135.wordpress.com

Github: https://github.com/maniamartial

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am an enthusiastic, reliable, self-motivated and proactive software developer with an eye for detail. I aim to exceed expectations over and above my normal duties and responsibilities. I am results-driven, hardworking, and a proven resource to ensure that a company enjoys a competitive edge at all levels. My goals in my developer career are to create and optimize the best web software for clients and maximize my training experience, program development skills, and abilities. Lastly, I desire to learn and work with experienced developers to gain more knowledge on solving problems using tech. I look forward to joining your team.

EDUCATION

Kenyatta University 2019 - Present

Computer Science

Nyang'ori School 2015 - 2018

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education Grade A-

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fruitful Labs | Nairobi, Kenya

Nov 2021 - Dec 2022

Backend Developer

- Created high-performance and scalable RESTful APIs for data-intensive applications.
- Built a microservice-based architecture to increase system efficiency and stability.
- Developed automated testing and deployment pipelines to reduce manual intervention and improve release quality.
- Debugged complex issues in the production environment and implemented permanent solutions to prevent recurrence.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver end-to-end software solutions.

Iconcept Media | California, USA

Nov 2021 - Dec 2022

Technical Writer

- Creating technical documentation such as user manuals, installation guides, and online help documentation.
- Collaborate with development teams to understand the technical details of products

• Translate that information into clear, concise, and accurate documentation for users.

Lux Academy | Nairobi, Kenya *Backend Developer Intern*

Feb 2021 - Aug 2021

- Designed, built, and implemented RESTful APIs that were secure, reliable, and easy to consume.
- Worked on optimizing the performance and scalability of existing applications to accommodate increasing user traffic.
- Working on SEO to create fast loading of pages

PROJECTS

- Have done almost 15 projects using various tools, GitHub (https://github.com/maniamartial)
- Find some of my certifications on LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-mania)

SKILLS

- Django python framework
- Pvthon
- Javascript(Mongodb, Express, Nodejs), HTML5, CSS3
- SQL(Postgresql, MYSQL, Sqlite, Mongodb)
- Docker
- Software Engineering Process

REFEREES

Anne Lwenya
President
Deborah Amoi Foundation
dafinternational@gmail.com
+254 798 205 169
+1 (661) 703-2657

Harun Mbaabu CEO Lux Tech Academy University of Nairobi mbaabuharun8@gmail.com +254 798 166 628 Jeremic Arose
Developer
Fruitfull Labs
arosejeremic5@gmail.com
+254 742 518807